ZACHARIAH SHAREK

sharek@gmail.com • (919) 757-4569

Entrepreneurial Carnegie Mellon Tepper Ph.D. that blends technology startup experience and an academic background in management and strategy to lead teams creating data-driven products. Focused on designing client solutions by understanding organizational and consumer needs combined with strong data analysis skills.

EXPERIENCE

• **Apturis**, A BBC seed funded marketing analytics startup *Founder & Executive Director*

Pittsburgh, PA 2/2016–current

- Recruited by senior leadership at the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) to form a company focusing on improving global marketing strategy and decision-making
- Developed a solution using novel data sources, enabling real-time global measurement of the BBC's marketing efforts & media properties
- Currently licensing the technology to the BBC and other media companies
- **Rhiza**, A Draper Triangle funded marketing analytics startup Senior Vice President of Product Strategy

Pittsburgh, PA 11/2014–1/2016

- Led a team of 18 product managers, developers and data scientists in creating products for data-driven marketing analysis for media ad sales clients; Resulted in 24 new customers and 200% increase in monthly recurring revenue
- Directed business development of partnerships with top providers of syndicated marketing data, including Nielsen, Rentrak, Experian and Polk
- Consulted with media clients to optimize ad sales revenue and consumer research; Increased success of ad sales pitches by 75%
- **CivicScience**, A NPD Group funded big data consumer insights startup *Director of Strategy & Innovation*

Pittsburgh, PA 3/2013–10/2014

- Led the company's consumer insights consulting team; Tripled consulting revenue within one year
- Created data products identifying persuadable consumers; Resulted in acquiring over 30 consumer goods clients, including General Mills, T-Mobile and Samsung
- Developed marketing strategy and ROI analytic models for healthcare clients using over 500 million insurance claims; Increased advertising ROI by over 50%
- Tepper School of Business, Carnegie Mellon University Researcher & Instructor

Pittsburgh, PA 7/2006–5/2012

- Research focus on strategy & management, especially judgment & decision-making
- Awarded \$223,000 National Science Foundation grant on behavioral biases in decisionmaking resulting in four papers & seven conference presentations
- Instructor for classes on management, decision-making and negotiations with teaching evaluations in top 10% of university

Zachariah Sharek

Experience continued

• Harvard Business School, Harvard University

Boston, MA

Research Associate

1/2006-7/2006

- Created models of media consumption from analysis of multi-terabyte datasets; including the largest ever dataset HBS had used for research
- Designed economic experiments investigating behavioral game theory, the results were used in three academic papers
- Managed experimental economic lab; Supervised three research assistants; Developed and administered over 25 experiments

Accenture
Consultant
Charlotte, NC
8/2003–7/2005

- Led an international team of 15 programmers & testers in successfully stress-testing an online-banking website with over \$300 billion of deposits
- Designed and lead implementation of mortgage securitization and re-underwriting software that processed up to \$10 billion of mortgages daily for a financial startup
- Created a statistical model determining which mortgages to re-underwrite; Resulted in 33% increase in mortgage securities processing speed

EDUCATION

• Tepper School of Business, Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

Ph.D., Organizational Behavior & Theory (Strategy & Management)

8/2006-5/2012

- Expertise: strategy, judgment & decision-making, behavioral economics, negotiations

• University of North Carolina

Chapel Hill, NC

MS, Information Science

8/2000-12/2002

BA, Economics & Philosophy

8/1996-12/1999

- Played Division 1 rugby; Selected to North Carolina All-Star team
- Developer on TeraScale Retrieval, a National Science Foundation funded project
- Transfered from Duke University after freshman year

Additional Information

Nonprofit Work: Director Emeritus of the Association for the Coral Environment, Advisor to the Executive Director of the Bahamas Reef Environment Education Fund (BREEF)

Activities: Statistical analysis for breast cancer research, competitive kettlebell lifting & instruction, designing board games